<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lukas&#39; Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lukas&#39; Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 17:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BentoCore - Making Your BentoBox Smarter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/09/29/bentocore-making-your-bentobox-smarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/09/29/bentocore-making-your-bentobox-smarter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post will be mostly about 3d printing air quality and especially air safety. Before starting I want to mention that I am no professional (far from it to be honest), I&amp;rsquo;m just a hobbyist focused on making my setup as safe as possible - so read the next lines with caution and do not take this as medical / health advice or anything more than a random blog post on the internet. As my two 3d printers are placed inside my &amp;ldquo;office&amp;rdquo; (it&amp;rsquo;s more a hobby room than an office, but let&amp;rsquo;s keep pretending) and I spend a significant amount of time inside this room, I wanted a way to measure air quality in my room.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Framing a Phone</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/09/28/framing-a-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/09/28/framing-a-phone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I received an iPhone 6s from a friend who couldn&amp;rsquo;t remember their iCloud password and since it was a 6s decided they didn’t want to bother with it anymore.. So the question then was what to do with it, of course keeping it for spare parts was an option, but since it was such an old phone I needed something better as it would mostly just collect dust waiting to donate some of its internals. After digging around online, I found the perfect answer: teardown art. Not only would it give new life to the old device, but I’d also end up with a unique piece of art for my home. Basically, the phone is disassembled into its pieces and then put on a nice template describing each part.  To really make this look good though it should be noted that the phone shouldn&amp;rsquo;t show visible defects/marks and should still have the original battery.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So, I Bought a P1S</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/09/12/so-i-bought-a-p1s/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/09/12/so-i-bought-a-p1s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the recent (or not so recent) BambuLab anniversary sale, I decided to buy a P1S. At the beginning, I was very unsure about buying it with the AMS or without, it is a lot of money for a hobby nevertheless. As my university time nears its end (currently just my Master Thesis is left to do) I decided to &amp;ldquo;reward&amp;rdquo; myself with the AMS on top of it - and luckily so.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/11/13/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/11/13/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;who-am-i&#34;&gt;Who am I&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hi, my name is Lukas, 24 years old and at the time of writing I am a CS masters student. I want to start this blog to share my enthusiuasm for various diy projects (though most of them probably will evolve around 3d printing or homelabing).&#xA;Maybe once or twice there will also be a little coding (maybe microcontroller based stuff, though I am not very expierenced with that). Mostly I see this as an opportunity to learn myself and share what I do for fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi 👋, I&amp;rsquo;m Lukas, a nearly-graduated CS student with a passion for HomeLab, 3D printing and the occiasional DIY project. Beyond that, I am currently developing &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/InventoryHero/InventoryHero&#34;target=&#34;_blank&#34;&#xA;  class=&#34;inline-flex items-center gap-1&#34;&#xA;&gt;InventoryHero&#xA;  &lt;svg id=&#34;external-link&#34; class=&#34;h-3 w-3 flex-shrink-0&#34;&#xA;    fill=&#34;none&#34;&#xA;    stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34;&#xA;    viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34;&gt;&lt;path fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34; d=&#34;M15 3h6v6m-11 5L21 3m-3 10v6a2 2 0 0 1-2 2H5a2 2 0 0 1-2-2V8a2 2 0 0 1 2-2h6&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;, which started as a university project but has since become a fun, hands-on learning experience for building real-world applications (also I am using it myself to keep track of, well my inventory).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
